<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Task Automation on Theoretically Josh</title><link>/tags/task-automation/</link><description>Recent content in Task Automation on Theoretically Josh</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 09:14:05 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/task-automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Clean Data for AI &amp; Automation: Best Practices &amp; Avoiding Automation Failures</title><link>/post/data-cleansing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 09:14:05 -0700</pubDate><guid>/post/data-cleansing/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the first steps to ensure your success when automating a process or using AI in your workflow is to have clean data.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-do-i-mean-by-clean-data">What do I mean by clean data?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Clean data is data that can be easily manipulated by software, such as AI, to provide meaningful and accurate results.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me tell you about an experience I had with data that wasn&amp;rsquo;t clean. I was tasked with automating the migration of data out of an old billing system into a new one. In the old system, &amp;ldquo;Contracts&amp;rdquo; were stored as free-form data. The client name and the products they purchased were also free-form text. This meant that if &amp;ldquo;Client A&amp;rdquo; originally purchased &amp;ldquo;Product A,&amp;rdquo; and later wanted &amp;ldquo;Product C&amp;rdquo; as well, an additional contract was created. This time the client was listed as &amp;ldquo;Client A LLC&amp;rdquo; with a product called &amp;ldquo;Service.&amp;rdquo; How would you go about determining what the client is contracted for? Well, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t take much for someone to recognize that &amp;ldquo;Client A&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Client A LLC&amp;rdquo; are actually the same company. I could have made part of the import process remove common suffixes like &amp;ldquo;LLC&amp;rdquo; when matching everything up. However, everything we sold was a &amp;ldquo;Service.&amp;rdquo; The only way to determine which service was purchased was to hope the salesperson remembered what it was the client bought. This was just one of many problems encountered with the data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automation: A Little Time Upfront and Save You Time and Your Sanity</title><link>/post/automate-and-save/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 09:15:05 -0700</pubDate><guid>/post/automate-and-save/</guid><description>&lt;p>Do you spend 10-20 minutes every morning just getting started with work? It’s a surprisingly common problem, and it’s costing you valuable time. You’re not alone. Countless professionals struggle with this repetitive routine. The good news is, automation can dramatically change this. It’s not just for large companies. Even a few minutes spent setting up simple automations can save you hours each week.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-few-minutes-can-save-you-hours">A Few Minutes Can Save You Hours&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Think about your process every morning when you first log into your computer to work. It may look something like this:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>