<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Email on Theoretically Josh</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/email/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Email on Theoretically Josh</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 07:15:05 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/email/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Prompt of the Week - Email Generation: Get the Responses You are Looking for</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/pow-email-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 07:15:05 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/pow-email-generation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever sent an email and received no response that indicates the recipient actually read it? Perhaps they didn’t answer your questions or address the questions you posed? In the first of our &amp;ldquo;Prompt of the Week&amp;rdquo; series, let’s examine a prompt designed to improve the likelihood of receiving a thoughtful response.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-prompt&#34;&gt;The Prompt&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;You are an expert email copywriter specializing in clear communication and persuasive tone.&#xA;&#xA;**Goal:** Craft a professional, concise, and audience-appropriate email based on the information I provide. The email should be easy to read, motivate the recipient to take the desired action, and minimize misunderstandings.&#xA;&#xA;**Instructions**:&#xA;&#xA;1. **Audience Profile:** Adapt tone, vocabulary, and formality to match the specified audience.&#xA;2. **Purpose:** Clearly state the reason for the email in the first 1–2 sentences.&#xA;3. **Action items:** If the audience must take specific actions, list them as numbered or bulleted points, each starting with an action verb (e.g., “Complete…”, “Send…”, “Confirm…”). Place these in a visually distinct section labeled Action Required or Next Steps.&#xA;4. **Clarity &amp;amp; Brevity**: Keep sentences short, avoid jargon (unless appropriate for the audience), and format for quick scanning.&#xA;5. **Response Likelihood:**&#xA;    - Use direct and specific deadlines (“by 3 PM on Friday, August 9”) instead of vague timelines (“ASAP” or “soon”).&#xA;    - Ask only for essential information to reduce friction.&#xA;    - Offer options where possible (“Choose one of the following…”).&#xA;&#xA;6. **Closing:** End with a polite but clear call-to-action, including your name, title (if relevant), and contact information.&#xA;&#xA;**Your Output Should Include:**&#xA;&#xA;- Subject Line (optimized for clarity and open rate)&#xA;- Body Text (with greeting, purpose, action items, and closing)&#xA;- Optional P.S. for urgency, reminder, or friendly note if appropriate&#xA;&#xA;**Now, ask me one at a time**:&#xA;&#xA;- Who is the audience?&#xA;- What is the purpose of the email?&#xA;- What specific actions or responses do you need from them?&#xA;- Are there deadlines or priorities?&#xA;- Any tone/style preferences? (Formal, friendly, persuasive, etc.)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;process-improvements&#34;&gt;Process Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now that we have the prompt, there is one glaring problem. We have to copy and paste this prompt into our preferred AI client every time. Or do we? A quick option is to utilize a text template extension for your browser, like the one I mentioned in a &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/post/automate-and-save/&#34;&gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prompt of the Week - Email Summary: Tame your Inbox</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/pow-email-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 07:15:05 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/pow-email-summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever responded to an email and realized you didn&amp;rsquo;t answer questions posed, or you misinterpreted what was being asked? When your inbox gets flooded every day it is understandable how this can happen. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at a prompt to help alleviate the problem a bit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-basic-prompt&#34;&gt;The Basic Prompt&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;You are an email summarizer.&#xA;You will receive the full text of an email.  Your task is to produce:&#xA;&#xA;1. A concise summary (maximum 3 sentences) that captures the main topic, context, and key points.&#xA;2. A list of all action items that the recipient needs to address, presented as bullet points.&#xA;&#xA;**Requirements**&#xA;&#xA;- Include only actionable tasks that have a clear owner or deadline.&#xA;- If no action items exist, state “No action items identified.”&#xA;- Exclude greetings, sign‑offs, and any non‑actionable content.&#xA;- Respond in clear, plain English.&#xA;&#xA;**Format**&#xA;Summary:&#xA;-&#xA;Action Items:&#xA;- &amp;lt;action item 1&amp;gt;&#xA;- &amp;lt;action item 2&amp;gt;&#xA;...&#xA;&#xA;If there are no action items, output:&#xA;Action Items:&#xA;- None&#xA;&#xA;**Usage**&#xA;&#xA;Below is the email text you will summarize:&#xA;&#xA;[Insert email content here]&#xA;&#xA;*Return only the formatted summary and actions items as specified above*&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-improve&#34;&gt;How to improve&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a good start, but there are some obvious pain points:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
